Jia-Wei Liao

📕 0939-580-280 💌 jw@cmlab.csie.ntu.edu.tw 🛅 jia-wei-liao 🜎 Jia-Wei-Liao 🏶 jia-wei-liao.github.io/

SUMMARY

Hi, I'm Jia-Wei. I'm currently a Ph.D. student at NTU CSIE, and I also served as a data analyst intern at Appier. I have hands-on experience in the field through internships. My research interests are in the areas of data science and computer vision. I am excited to apply my skills and knowledge to new challenges and opportunities in the industry, particularly in these fields.

EXPERIENCE

Taiwan, Taipei **Appier** Data Analyst Internship in AiDeal ML Team · SaaS · E-commerce · MarTech Aug 2022 - Present

- 1. **Feature Engineering:** Develop new features to improve the accuracy of the model.
- 2. Machine Learning: Develop a model to detect the tendency of users to purchase items.
- 3. Data Science: Develop evaluation metrics to measure the cost-benefit trade-off of the implementation.
- 4. Data Analysis: Develop new scripts to assist in data analysis and utilize web scraping to detect patterns on web pages.

TMBA Taiwan, Taipei Member of Strategic Marketing Department Jul 2021 - Present **National Center for Theoretical Sciences** Taiwan, Taipei

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

- Undergraduate Summer Research Project
- 1. Design a new variational-based image denoising model demonstrate its feasibility.
- 2. Design an end-to-end image stitching algorithm and improve computational efficiency.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University Taiwan, Taipei PhD Student of Computer Science and Information Engineering · GPA: 4.3 / 4.3 · Ranking: 1 / 18 Sep 2022 - present Research: Machine Learning, and Computer Vision

Courses: Computer Vision, and Information Retrieval and Extraction

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Taiwan, Hsinchu Master of Applied Mathematics · GPA: 4.28 / 4.3 · Ranking: 1 / 27 Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

Research: Computer Vision, Deep Learning, and Scientific Computing

Courses: Machine Learning, Data Science, Data Mining, Advanced Probability, Matrix Computing, and Numerical Optimization

National Taiwan Normal University

Taiwan, Taipei Bachelor of Mathematics with Educational Program · GPA: 4.06 / 4.3 · Ranking: 3 / 89 *Aug* 2016 - Jun 2020

PROJECTS

• Crop Image Recognition · Python · 🗘 · 🖺	Dec 2022
• Interpretive Information Labeling for Natural Language Processing · Python · 🕥	Dec 2022
• Low-power Lane Semantic Segmentation · Python · 🕥	Jun 2022
• Contour Segmentation for Spread Through Air Spaces in Lung Adenocarcinoma · Python · 🗘	Jun 2022
• Supervised Learning for Few-Shot Orchid types Classification with Prior Guided Feature · Python · 😯	Jun 2022
• Ultrasound Nerve Segmentation · Python · 🞧 · 🖺	Jan 2022
• Sentiment Analysis of Food Reviews on Yelp Platform · Python	Dec 2021
• Low-rank Matrix Approximation for Recommender System · MATLAB · 🕥	Dec 2021
• Mean Curvature Flow on Graphs for Image Denoising · MATLAB · 😱	Jan 2021
• Dictionary Learning for Image Inpainting · MATLAB · 🗘	Dec 2020

SKILLS

- Programming Language: Python, MATLAB, C, C++, SQL, MongoDB and LaTeX
- Framework: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, and Scikit
- **Developer Tool:** Git, VS Code, Jupyter, and Vim

HONORS

• AI CUP 2022 Fall Competition Honorable Mention Award * 3 · 🏶	Jan 2023
Diligent Doctoral Student Scholarship ·	Jan 2023
• AI CUP 2022 Spring Competition Merit Award and MATLAB Outstanding Application First Price • 🏶	Jul 2022
• TWSIAM 2022 Paper Poster Contest Second Place Award • •	Jul 2022
• Academia Sinica Dr. Chou-Hung-Ching Scholarship · 🏶	Dec 2021